SAEED SAAD AL-MOURAD

Technical Support Leader

EXECUTIVE SYNOPSIS

A **performance-driven Computer Science professional** with 16+ years of rich experience in leading a service driven call center operations and providing high-end technical support - implementing strategic projects that support business goals, managing existing systems that support operations and security and supporting end users by addressing issues and minimizing downtime.

Commanding on-going project management, execution of programs considering timelines, changes/improvements to accelerate business growth along with client arsenal.

Mastered robust data analysis of key operational and business metrics, identifying opportunities for innovation and quantifying the value of the opportunity, thus delivering key capabilities in support of the business strategy and facilitating management with enhanced decision making.

Consistently studying new innovations in network administration techniques, keeping informed of advances of technology and equipment; assisting in networking infrastructure improvements and in the design of new systems.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Technical Excellence
- Customer Service
- Project Management
- Data Analysis
- Call Center Management
- Customer Experience & Loyalty
- Escalation Containment
- Performance KPIs
- Intelligence & Insights
- Resources Optimization
- Drive Service & Quality
- Training and Development
- Team Building & Management
- Leadership

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Technical Support

2021 - Present

Emdad Alkhebrat, Jeddah, KSA

Emdad Al Khebrat is a subsidiary company completely owned by Elm Co. It was established to provide quality manpower services to the different sectors in the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia.

Accomplishments:

- Served as an escalation point in support of high-risk and complex technical challenges.
- Instrumental in creating and embedding methodology and practice of Operational Excellence across the Call Center.

Responsibilities:

- Commanding Customer Support initiatives, delivering a wide-range of professional IT services and ensuring 100% uptime/stability and providing 24/7 support.
- Developing project plans, determining methodology used on the project, resource planning, scheduling and managing development timelines.
- Spearheading Call Center operations, focusing on exemplary customer service delivery, sustainability and people management.
- Data Analysis expert, enabling organization capture and capitalize on big data. Leveraging a unified reporting and analytics solutions/software: Service Desk, Frisco, eHaj, Booking systems and AVAYA.
- Setting up and managing IIS manager. Aiding users to securely manage remote web sites and applications on Internet Information Server (IIS) servers.
- Facilitating customer care quality assurance using AVAYA Call Center. Strategically led key initiatives and transformation projects to improve operations effectiveness and efficiency and improve customer experience by utilizing modern contact/call center platforms.
- Providing strong, dynamic leadership that mentors, develops and guides team to deliver an excellent customer service.

Technical Support

2018 - 2021

SEJEL, Jeddah, KSA

Sejel is an established company focusing on Management Consulting services, enterprise technology solutions, and turn key solutions for both public & private sector companies. It specializes in implementing innovative e-solutions, improve key management, financial and operational metrics and provide a quick Return on Investment (ROI).

Accomplishments:

- Provided high-value IT services, managing technically advanced cost-efficient, state-of-theart systems & processes.
- Played a key role in delivering class-leading quality-oriented customer service which helped in driving customer loyalty and support continued business.
- Recognized for successfully managing and directing the assigned project resources to overcome "triple constraints"—project scope, time and cost.
- Shouldered onus to continuously exceed the call center productivity, targets, service and quality levels.

Responsibilities:

- Drove customer success through enhanced Consumer Services design & delivery planning, resulting in protection and enhancing revenue.
- Provided analytical or specialized technical solutions, with a goal of demonstrating innovative solutions and exceptional value-addition to address the client's objectives.
- Directed Call Center initiatives, attained monthly SLA set for Call Center by monitoring performance in respect of timeliness, responsiveness, accuracy and control.
- Produced leading-edge analytics, quality monitoring reports & feedback results, used software: Service Desk, Frisco, eHaj, Booking systems and AVAYA.
- Continually strove to improve operating effectiveness, customer experience by strategically handling complaint management, increasing quality of resolution & related satisfaction scores thereby driving complaints down.

Systems and Network Administrator

2012 - 2018

Rose Mary Est., Jeddah, KSA

RoseMary Paris is a French house of perfumes, it owns 65 stores around the world.

Accomplishments:

- Played a key role in designing and implementing a network and server room and monitoring them
- Defined system architecture, responsible for the technical design, planning, implementation and the highest level of performance tuning and recovery procedures for mission critical computer systems.

Responsibilities:

- Kept IT strategy aligned with the changing organizational needs, suggested new upgraded products for better performance and efficiency.
- Managed all applications (Al Amin for finance & accounting, attendance application, security, team viewer and Dyndns).
- Managed Rose Mary social media channels Facebook webpage, Twitter as well as the website HTML customization.
- Built a network between branches over company domain.
- Acted as a subject matter expert, facilitator and coordinated system training initiatives for the Salespersons and Users.
 - Provided instructions for new system applications, development, process changes, enhancements and releases.
- Managed Microsoft and godaddy accounts for Rose Mary Company. Administrated SQL 2008.

Previous Professional Experiences:

- 2007 2012: Systems Office Manager, Ebaa House Company, Jeddah
- 2006 2007: Help Desk Officer, Raja Mouneer Est. Jeddah
- 2006: Trainer, Al Khobara Company Jeddah

EDUCATION

• Bachelor degree of Computer Science, American University of London, 2008

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

PMP Training Course

PERSONAL INFORMATION

• **Nationality:** Syrian

• **Date of Birth**: 1983 (39)

• **Languages:** Arabic & English